hey guys this looks like a fun one it's
got a whole bunch of stuff going on and
it's asking for the area of this blue
triangle if you want to try it on your
own pause it right now CU I'm going to
solve it in 3 2 1 so first let's look at
this square right here this side is
equal to four so this side right here is
also equal to four next I want to look
at this rhombus right here let's verify
that it's a square we know that if this
is a right angle this is also a right
angle in a rhombus opposite angles are
congruent so these two would be
congruent and these two would also be
congruent so we know that rhombus is a
square and then I want to focus on this
triangle this is a right triangle so we
know that we can use the Pythagorean
theorem so A2 plus b^2 is going to equal
c^2 and these two are equal to each
other so let's call them both X so we
can say x^2 + x^2 is equal to 4^2 X2 +
X2 is equal to 2x^2 and 4^2 is equal to
16 after we divide both sides by two we
get x^2 is equal to 8 and after we
square root both sides we get X is equal
to theare < TK of 8 so let's update both
of these X's to s < TK of 8 next let's
go back to this square right here we
know these two sides are four this side
is also equal to four and now let's look
at this right angle again this diagonal
is going to BCT that right angle so both
of these will be 45° and then in this
Square we also have a right angle and if
this is 45 that means this last angle
must also be 45° so we have each of
these angles equal to 45° if we focus on
this triangle we can figure out this
obtuse angle is equal to the sum of
these three which is
135° and now since this is an obtuse
triangle we have to use the law of
cosiness so if we call the sides a b and
c and this angle Theta the law of
cosiness tells us c^2 is = to a 2 + b^2
- 2 * a * B cosine of that angle Theta
so we're going to use this to solve this
side C so let's give ourselves some room
and a is equal to the square < TK of 8
so in the place of each of these A's
we'll plug in square < TK of 8 and then
B is equal to four so in the place of
these B's we'll plug in four and then
Theta is equal to 135 deg
< TK of 82 is equal to 8 + 4 2 is equal
to 16 and then we're going to subtract
all this 2 * 4 is equal 8 and then we
still have the < TK of 8 and to get
cosine of 135 we can look at the unit
circle to get < tk2 over2 and then 8 +
16 is equal to 24 and then this negative
time this negative will give us a
positive and all this is going to be a
fraction we can copy down the 8un 8 * <
tk2 will give usun 16 and this two will
still be in the denominator this otk 16
is equal to 4 * 4 is equal to 32 and 32
/ 2 is 16 24 + 16 is equal to 40 and
after we square root both sides we get C
is equal to the squ < TK of 40 so we can
update this side length C to be square <
TK of 40 and now let's focus on this
square right here since this side isqu <
TK of 40 this side will also be squ < TK
of 40 and then we're ready to focus on
this right triangle and because it's a
right triangle we can do Pythagorean
theorem we'll assign a b and c to the
sides C is equal to < TK of 40 so we can
plug in < TK of 40 here and then B is
equal to > of8 so we'll plug in < TK of
8 and then we'll just copy down the a^ S
the < TK of 402 is 40 and then squ < TK
of 8^2 is equal to 8 and then let's copy
down the A2 and then we can subtract 8
from both sides and we get a^2 is equal
to 32 and then after we square root both
sides we get a is equal to square < TK
of 32 so we can update this side a to be
square < TK of 32 and now since we have
these two sides we're ready to find the
area of this triangle the area is equal
to 1/2 base time height where the base
is the < TK of 32 and the height is the
< TK of 8 we can combine the < TK of 32
and the < TK of8 so we end up with the <
TK of 256 and then theun of 256 is 16
and 1 12 of 16 is 8 we'll give it a
label of centimet squar and that is the
answer to our question let's put a box
around it the area of this blue triangle
is 8 cm squared how exciting